ryobitools.com 2019-03-28

# RYOBI Tools

##### Last modified: March 28, 2018

One World Technologies, Inc. (“Company” or “we” or “our” or “us”) respects your privacy and is committed to protecting it through our compliance with this policy.

What is covered by this policy?  
What information do we collect about you and how we collect it?  
How do we use your information?  
When and how do we disclose your information?  
What are your choices about how we use and disclose your information?  
How do you remove or correct your personal information?  
What is excluded from this policy?  
Will this privacy policy change?  
How to contact us?

* * *

#### What is covered by this policy?

This policy describes the types of information we may collect from you or that you may provide when you visit the Company’s website, ryobitools.com, or use our services or software that we control, including but not limited to the RYOBI™ Phone Works™ application(collectively, our “Services”) and our practices for collecting, using, maintaining, protecting, and disclosing that information.

This policy applies to information we collect through online means and does not apply to information collected offline or through third parties.

Please read this policy carefully to understand our policies and practices regarding your information and how we will treat it. If you do not agree with our policies and practices, your choice is not to use our Services. By accessing or using our Services, you agree to this privacy policy.

#### What information do we collect about you and how we collect it?

We collect several types of information from and about you, including information:

  * by which you may be personally identified, such as name, postal address, e-mail address, and telephone number (“personal information”);
  * that is about you but individually does not identify you, such as gender and birth date;
  * about the Ryobi products that you own such as product model numbers, serial numbers and purchase location;
  * about your internet connection, browser, IP address, any files you download or view, your path through our website, the date, time and frequency you spend accessing our website and the length of time you spend reviewing certain features; 
  * about your actual physical location using various technologies to determine location, including IP address; and/or
  * you voluntarily provide us, including through surveys, such as income, dwelling type, occupation, preferences, interests and opinions.

We collect this information:

  * Directly from you when you provide it to us.
  * Automatically as you navigate through the website. Information collected automatically may include usage details, IP addresses, and information collected through cookies, web beacons, and other tracking technologies.

The technologies we use for automatic data collection may include:

  * Cookies (or browser cookies). A cookie is a small file placed on the hard drive of your computer. You may refuse to accept browser cookies by activating the appropriate setting on your browser. However, if you select this setting you may be unable to access certain parts of our Services. Unless you have adjusted your browser setting so that it will refuse cookies, our system will issue cookies when you direct your browser to our Services.
  * Flash Cookies. Certain features of our Services may use local stored objects (or Flash cookies) to collect and store information about your preferences and navigation to, from, and on our Services. Flash cookies are not managed by the same browser settings as are used for browser cookies.
  * Web Beacons. Our Services may contain small electronic files known as web beacons (also referred to as clear gifs, pixel tags, and single-pixel gifs) that permit the Company, for example, to count users who have visited those pages or opened an email and for other related website statistics.

We do not collect personal information automatically, but we may tie this information to personal information about you that we collect from other sources or you provide to us.

We do not track you over time and movement across third party websites to provide targeted advertising and therefore we do not respond to Do Not Track (DNT) signals.

#### How do we use your information?

We use information that we collect about you or that you provide to us, including any personal information:

  * To present our Services to you.
  * To provide you with information or services that you request from us.
  * To provide you with information about our goods and services that may be of interest to you. You may opt-out from receiving emails regarding our products and services by unsubscribing.
  * To fulfill any other purpose for which you provide it
  * To aggregate with other data to better understand purchasing patterns and customer personas.
  * To carry out our rights arising from any contracts entered into between you and us.
  * In any other way we may describe when you provide the information.
  * For any other purpose with your consent.

#### When and how do we disclose your information?

We may disclose aggregated information about our users, and information that does not identify any individual, without restriction.

We may disclose personal information that we collect or you provide as described in this privacy policy:

  * To contractors, service providers, and other third parties we use to support our business.
  * To a buyer or other successor in the event of a merger, divestiture, restructuring, reorganization, dissolution, or other sale or transfer of some or all of our assets, whether as a going concern or as part of bankruptcy, liquidation, or similar proceeding, in which personal information held by us about our Services users is among the assets transferred.
  * To fulfill the purpose for which you provide it.
  * For any other purpose disclosed by us when you provide the information.
  * With your consent.

We may also disclose your personal information:

  * To comply with any court order, law, or legal process, including to respond to any government or regulatory request.
  * To enforce or apply our terms of use and other agreements.
  * If we believe disclosure is necessary or appropriate to protect the rights, property, or safety of us, our customers, or others. This includes exchanging information with other companies and organizations for the purposes of fraud protection and credit risk reduction

#### What are your choices about how we use and disclose your information?

At the time when you provide personal information to us, or when you register for an account on our website to use the services which we provide, you agree that we can communicate with you electronically regarding your use of the website or our products and services. However, we strive to provide you with choices regarding the personal information you provide to us. We have created mechanisms to provide you with the following control over your information:

  * **Tracking Technologies and Advertising.** You can set your browser to refuse all or some browser cookies, or to alert you when cookies are being sent. To learn how you can manage your Flash cookie settings, visit the Flash player settings page on Adobe’s [website](http://www.macromedia.com/support/documentation/en/flashplayer/help/settings_manager07.html). If you disable or refuse cookies, please note that some parts of this site may then be inaccessible or not function properly.
  * **Email Communications.** If you do not want to receive emails from us regarding special offers or about our products and services, you can unsubscribe from this service using the unsubscribe option provided in the email. We will still send you emails regarding your products if you registered your product, such as warranty and safety information, and emails in response to your communications to us or related to the purpose for which you supplied us with your email address.

#### How do you remove or correct your personal information?

You may change or remove personal information stored in your account by logging into your account and modifying the information. If you wish to have us delete your personal information that you have provided to us, you may contact us using the information in the How to contact us? section. We may not accommodate a request to change information if we believe the change would violate any law or legal requirement.

#### What is excluded from this policy?

  * **Third Party Sites.** Our website may contain links to websites owned by other companies. We do not control or endorse and are not responsible for the privacy practices of other sites or third parties to whom you may link from our website. This policy is not intended to describe data handling procedures for information collected by other linked websites or business partners.
  * **Social Media.** When you use some applications or post on a social networking service, the personal information and content you share is visible to other users and can be read, collected, or used by them. This may include your name, email address, photo, gender, birthday, location, an ID associated with the third party platform or social media account user files, like photos and videos, your list of friends or connections, people you follow and/or who follow you, or your posts or “likes.” You are responsible for the personal information you choose to share or submit in these instances. For a description on how social media services and other third party platforms, plug-ins, integrations or applications handle your information, please refer to their respective privacy policies and terms of use, which may permit you to modify your privacy settings.
  * **Children Under the Age of 13.** Our Services are not intended for children under 13 years of age. No one under age 13 should provide any personal information to or through any of the Services. We do not knowingly collect personal information from children under 13. If you are under 13, do not use our Services or provide any information to or through our Services. If we learn we have collected or received personal information from a child under 13 without verification of parental consent, we will delete that information. If you believe we might have any information from or about a child under 13, please contact us using the contact information in the Contact Information section below.
  * **Users Outside of the U.S.** If you live outside the United States (including Canada, Mexico and the European Economic Area), and you use our Services, or provide us with personal information through our website, such information will be handled in accordance with this policy. THE SITES ARE GOVERNED BY AND OPERATED IN ACCORDANCE WITH UNITED STATES LAW. BY USING OUR WEBSITE AND SERVICES OR GIVING US YOUR PERSONAL INFORMATION, YOU ARE DIRECTLY TRANSFERRING YOUR PERSONAL INFORMATION AND OTHER INFORMATION TO US IN THE UNITED STATES WHERE OUR CENTRAL DATABASE OPERATES. BY USING OUR WEBSITE AND SERVICES, YOU ACKNOWLEDGE THAT THE UNITED STATES MAY NOT HAVE THE SAME LEVEL OF DATA PROTECTION AS YOUR JURISDICTION AND YOU AGREE AND EXPLICITLY CONSENT TO YOUR PERSONAL INFORMATION BEING COLLECTED, PROCESSED AND TRANSFERRED IN ACCORDANCE WITH THIS PRIVACY POLICY AND SUBJECT TO UNITED STATES LAWS. You are solely responsible for compliance with any data protection or privacy obligations in your jurisdiction when you use the Services, website, or provide us with personal information. Regardless of where we transfer your information, we still protect your information in the manner described in this policy.

#### Will this privacy policy change?

This privacy policy may change from time-to-time. It is our policy to post any changes we make to our privacy policy on this page. The date the privacy policy was last revised is identified at the top of the page. You are responsible for ensuring we have an up-to-date active and deliverable email address for you, and for periodically visiting our privacy policy to check for any changes.

#### How to contact us?

To ask questions or comment about this privacy policy and our privacy practices, contact us at:

One World Technologies, Inc.  
Attention: LEGAL DEPARTMENT  
1428 Pearman Dairy Road  
Anderson, South Carolina 29625
